Guide to the Basil Davenport Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- General Correspondence, 1919-1964; Series III; 1.6; (4 boxes)
  - Fadiman, Clifton, 1953-1958 (Box 16, Folder 227)
  - Fales, Edward D., 1955 (Box 16, Folder 228)
  - Farish, Hunter Dickinson, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 229)
  - Farnell, Lewis N., 1928 (Box 16, Folder 230)
  - Farrar, John Chipman, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 231)
  - Fatheree, Howard R., 1942, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 232)
  - Fisher, Dorothy (Canfield), 1954, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 233)
  - Foster, Russell, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 234)
  - Flaccus, Elmer William, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 235)
  - Ford, Anne, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 236)
  - Geve, T., 1959 (Box 16, Folder 237)
  - Gibbs, Angelica, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 238)
  - Gimbel, Richard, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 239)
  - Glennon, John, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 240)
  - Goertz, Suzanne (Nettel), [1949] (Box 16, Folder 241)
  - Gomot, Pierre, 1946-1955 (Box 16, Folder 242)
  - Grauer, Benjamin Franklin, undated (Box 16, Folder 243)
  - Greig, Peter, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 244)
  - Grimshaw, Peggy, 1956, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 245)
  - Haight, Gordon Sherman, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 246)
  - Hamilton, Schyler, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 247)
  - Hamlin, Mary P., 1926 (Box 16, Folder 248)
  - Handley-Taylor, Geoffrey, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 249)
  - Hanna, Edith, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 250)
  - Harfield, Henry David, [1959] (Box 16, Folder 251)
  - Hartwell, David, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 252)
  - Hausmann, Emil, 1948, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 253)
  - Heard, Richard, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 254)
  - Hêbert, Charles, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 255)
  - Heiberg, Harold, 1944 (Box 16, Folder 256)
  - Hein, Louis J., 1960 (Box 16, Folder 257)
  - Henning, Alison (Peake), 1940-1957 (Box 16, Folder 258)
  - Henning, Basil Duke, 1954, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 259)
  - Henning, Cameron Hunt, 1959-1960 (Box 16, Folder 260)
  - Henning, Julia, undated (Box 16, Folder 261)
  - Herbert, Sir Alan Patrick, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 262)
  - Herbert, Roy A., 1956 (Box 16, Folder 263)
    General note
    To Bennett Cerf, ref. to Davenport
  - Highet, Gilbert, 1955, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 264)
  - Hildebrand, Page, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 265)
  - Hill, Jeanette, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 266)
  - Hobson, Wilder, 1929 (Box 16, Folder 267)
  - Holden, Raymond Peckham, 1952-1963 (Box 16, Folder 268)
  - Holden, Sally H., 1942, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 269)
  - Howard, Frances (Minturn), 1951 (Box 16, Folder 270)
  - Howe, Dudley, [1958] (Box 16, Folder 271)
  - Humphreys, Joseph, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 272)
  - Huntsman, Leontine, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 273)
  - Information Please (subject), 1939-1940 (Box 16, Folder 274)
  - James, Edwin, 1947-1963 (Box 16, Folder 275)
  - Johnson, Thor, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 276)
  - Jones, Geoffrey, 1956-1957 (Box 16, Folder 277)
  - Jo[y]nes, Helen (Belknap), 1947 (Box 16, Folder 278)
  - Kemp, Earl, 1957-1958 (Box 16, Folder 279)
  - Kilgallen, Dorothy, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 280)
  - Kilmer, Annie (Kilburn), 1931 (Box 16, Folder 281)
  - Kimball, Chase, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 282)
  - Kirstein, William A., 1940-1960 (Box 16, Folder 283)
  - Klass, Fred, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 284)
  - Kleinpeter, Charles, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 285)
  - Knauth, Arnold Whitman, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 286)
  - Knollenberg, Bernhard, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 287)
  - Knott, Richard G., 1919 (Box 16, Folder 288)
  - Korshak, Melvin, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 289)
  - Kuehn, Helen (Dowling), [1959] (Box 16, Folder 290)
  - Laney, Francis T., 1944 (Box 16, Folder 291)
  - Lansing, Alfred, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 292)
  - Lardner, John, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 293)
  - Laurin, Richard K., 1954 (Box 16, Folder 294)
  - Lee, Mable A., 1957 (Box 16, Folder 295)
  - Leiper, Maria, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 296)
  - Lenard, Alexander, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 297)
  - Lescher, Robert, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 298)
  - Ley, Willy, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 299)
  - Leys, Katherine, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 300)
  - Lopatnikoff, Sally, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 301)
  - Libby, Herbert Carlyle, 1945, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 302)
  - Loveman, Amy, 1936-1951 (Box 16, Folder 303)
  - Lowe, William, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 304)
  - Lucius, James B., undated (Box 16, Folder 305)
  - Lucas, Frank Laurence, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 306)
  - McCreary, Miss, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 307)
  - MacDonald, Darcy B., 1934 (Box 16, Folder 308)
  - MacGregor, Willard, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 309)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 310)
  - McMahon, Nell (Russell), 1940, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 311)
  - McNeil, Joseph, 1938-1963 (Box 16, Folder 312)
  - Maggio, Joseph, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 313)
  - Mansbridge, Anthony, [1942] (Box 16, Folder 314)
  - Mansbridge, Ronald, 1943-1964 (Box 16, Folder 315)
  - Marshall, Edison, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 316)
  - Martin, Mr. E., 1940 (Box 17, Folder 317)
  - Martyn, Wyndham, 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 318)
  - Mazzeo, Henry, 1960-1964 (Box 17, Folder 319)
  - Mendes, Vincent, 1960-1963 (Box 17, Folder 320)
  - Mezzotero, Richard F., 1952 (Box 17, Folder 321)
  - Meyer, Fred, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 322)
  - Michener, James Albert, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 323)
  - Montgomery, Claudia and Floyd, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 324)
  - Moore, Elizabeth, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 325)
  - Morrison, Wendy and Kathy, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 326)
  - Morse, William, 1956, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 327)
  - Mossiker, Frances, 1960-1961 (Box 17, Folder 328)
  - Neal, Helen (Howell), 1955 (Box 17, Folder 329)
  - Nelson, Gene, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 330)
  - Nelson, George J., 1960 (Box 17, Folder 331)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 332)
  - The New Yorker, 1952-1956 (Box 17, Folder 333)
  - Nielsen, Aksel Jørgen, 1953-1962 (Box 17, Folder 334)
  - Noonan, Edward J., 1957 (Box 17, Folder 335)
  - Norman, William, 1957, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 336)
  - North, Sterling, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 337)
  - Norton, Mearl E., 1959 (Box 17, Folder 338)
  - O'Brien, J. A., 1958 (Box 17, Folder 339)
  - Ogburn, Charlton, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 340)
  - Osborne, Anne (Riggs), 1963 (Box 17, Folder 341)
  - Other Worlds (magazine), 1950 (Box 17, Folder 342)
  - Owens, Bea, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 343)
  - Pagenstecher, Bernard, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 344)
  - Paine, Alfred W., 1940 (Box 17, Folder 345)
  - Paul, Louis, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 346)
  - Peña, Joseph, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 347)
  - Petersen, Curtis A., 1959 (Box 17, Folder 348)
  - Pheelan, R. A., 1954 (Box 17, Folder 349)
  - Phelps, William Lyon, 1933-1942 (Box 17, Folder 350)
  - Piper, Miss M. M., 1937 (Box 17, Folder 351)
  - Platt Jr., S. Phelps, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 352)
  - The Players Club, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 353)
  - Plummer, Richard W., 1957 (Box 17, Folder 354)
  - Poland, Leland S., 1959 (Box 17, Folder 355)
  - Police Athletic League, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 356)
  - Potter, Alice (Osterhoudt), 1960 (Box 17, Folder 357)
  - Pratt, Inga (Stephens), 1956 (Box 17, Folder 358)
  - Pratt, Fletcher, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 359)
  - Purrington, Richard, 1956-1960 (Box 17, Folder 360)
  - Putnam, Howard Phelps, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 361)
  - Quick, Dorothy, [1950] (Box 17, Folder 362)
  - Reader's Digest, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 363)
  - Reichard, J. D., 1947 (Box 17, Folder 364)
  - Renault, Mary, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 365)
  - Rice, Jane, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 366)
  - Rich, Louise (Dickinson), 1955 (Box 17, Folder 367)
  - Riggs, Anthony, [1955]-1958 (Box 17, Folder 368)
  - Riggs, George Overton, 1932-1959 (Box 17, Folder 369)
  - Riggs, Imogen [Jean], 1942-1960 (Box 17, Folder 370-371)
  - Riggs, Mary V., 1943-1959 (Box 17, Folder 372)
  - Riggs, Phillis, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 373)
  - Riggs, Robert, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 374)
  - Riggs, Scott, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 375)
  - Roberts, Mr., 1955 (Box 17, Folder 376)
  - Rogers, John Stratford, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 377)
  - Rollins, Carl Purrington, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 378)
  - Rosin, Kathy (Scherman), 1945 (Box 17, Folder 379)
  - Rutledge, Miss, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 380)
  - Salinger, J. D. (Jerome David), 1946-1956 (Box 17, Folder 381)
  - The Saturday Review, 1949, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 382)
  - Scaife, Roger Livingston, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 383)
  - Schafer, Eleanor Calverley, 1955, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 384)
  - Scherman, Bernadine (Kielty), 1950-1955 (Box 17, Folder 385)
  - Scherman, Harry, [1943] (Box 18, Folder 386)
  - Scherman, Thomas, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 387)
  - Schneider, Evelyn J., 1948 (Box 18, Folder 388)
  - Schodt, Edward W. and Margie, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 389)
  - Schwed, Frederick, [1941], 1951 (Box 18, Folder 390)
  - Scithers, George H., [1960]-1961 (Box 18, Folder 391)
  - Shaffer, Isidor, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 392)
  - Shea, J. Vernon, 1952-1953 (Box 18, Folder 393)
  - Sherwood, Lorraine, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 394)
  - Simon, Richard Leo, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 395)
  - Slater, I. H., 1959-1961 (Box 18, Folder 396)
  - Sloane, Jessie, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 397)
  - Sloane, Julia [Julie], 1939-1959 (Box 18, Folder 398)
  - Sloane, William (Milligan III), 1941-1964 (Box 18, Folder 399)
  - Smith, Edgar, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 400)
  - Smith, George O., 1959 (Box 18, Folder 401)
  - Speare, Dorothy, 1936-1951 (Box 18, Folder 402)
  - Spencer, Page, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 403)
  - Stevens, George, 1939, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 404)
  - Stevenson, Donald M., 1954-1955 (Box 18, Folder 405)
  - Stewart, Sy S., 1959 (Box 18, Folder 406)
  - Stockman, Erling B., 1959 (Box 18, Folder 407)
  - Stoebe, Mary, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 408)
  - Stone, Martin, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 409)
  - Strode-Jackson, Arnold N. S., 1957 (Box 18, Folder 410)
  - Sullivan, Ed, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 411)
  - Swanson, Martin J., 1961 (Box 18, Folder 412)
  - Sweet, Henry Gordon, [1941] (Box 18, Folder 413)
  - Tabakow, Lou, undated (Box 18, Folder 414)
  - Taylor, Lois (Cole), 1955 (Box 18, Folder 415)
  - Thomas, Edmond George, 1942-1963 (Box 18, Folder 416)
  - Thomas, Michael Stanley, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 417)
  - Thompson, Morton, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 418)
  - Tuck, Donald H., 1960 (Box 18, Folder 419)
  - Tuttle, Frank Day, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 420)
  - U.S. Internal Revenue Service, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 421)
  - Valleé, William Lynch, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 422)
  - Van Allen, Eleanor, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 423)
  - Van Cleve, Charles Fowler, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 424)
  - Vandercook, Margaret O'Bannon (Womack), 1952 (Box 18, Folder 425)
  - Walbridge, Earle Francis, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 426)
  - Wallace, William Sanford, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 427)
  - Ward, Charles Henshaw, [1932-1933] (Box 18, Folder 428)
  - Waterbury, Louise S., 1939-1950 (Box 18, Folder 429)
  - Watkins, David Roy, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 430)
  - Weaver, Sylvester L., 1956, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 431)
  - Wellman, Manly Wade, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 432)
  - Welsh, Paul E., 1945-1958 (Box 18, Folder 433)
  - Westcott, Jeffrey, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 434)
  - Westcott, John and Mary, [1944]-1958 (Box 18, Folder 435)
  - Westcott, John M., [1938]-1962 (Box 18, Folder 436)
  - Westcott, Mary, 1956-1961 (Box 18, Folder 437)
  - White, Jon Ewbank Manship, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 438)
  - White, Theodore Harold, 1951-1961 (Box 18, Folder 439)
  - White, William Anthony Parkes, 1949-1957 (Box 18, Folder 440)
  - Whitehead, Thomas M., 1963 (Box 18, Folder 441)
  - Willard, Winifred, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 442)
  - Williams, Donald R., 1956 (Box 18, Folder 443)
  - Williams, John L. B., 1954 (Box 18, Folder 444)
  - Williams, Wilma (Mrs. Joseph F. Williams), 1955 (Box 18, Folder 445)
  - Windham, Donald, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 446)
  - Winslow Insurance Agency, 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 447)
  - Wing, Donald Goddard, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 448)
  - Wing, Paul, 1939 (Box 18, Folder 449)
  - [Wolff], Julian, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 450)
  - Wood, Scott, 1954-1955 (Box 18, Folder 451)
  - Woodbridge, John E., 1958 (Box 18, Folder 452)
  - Woolley, Edgar Montillon, 1943-1961 (Box 18, Folder 453)
  - Wroth, Peregrine, 1960-1964 (Box 18, Folder 454)
  - Wroth, Rufus, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 455)
  - Wuerpel, Gay B., 1953 (Box 18, Folder 456)
  - Yale University (President and Fellows), 1923 (Box 18, Folder 457)
  - Young, Clifton H., 1938, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 458)
  - Young, Marion W., 1953 (Box 18, Folder 459)
  - Zeta Psi, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 460)
  - Zlater, Gilbert P., 1947 (Box 18, Folder 461)
  - Zlater, Martin, 1951, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 462)
  - Zukofsky, Louis, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 463)
- Diaries, 1925-1964; Series IV; 0.8; (2 boxes)
  A loose-leaf record of Davenport's day-to-day activities, commencing in 1925 and extending from 1935 through 1964. There are numerous long gaps in the record, when Davenport was absent from New York, traveling, vacationing or serving in the second world war.
  - 1-40, 1925 (Box 19, Folder 464)
  - 41-60, 1935 (Box 19, Folder 465)
  - 61-193, 1938-1946 (Box 19, Folder 466)
  - 194-334, 1947-1948 (Box 19, Folder 467)
  - 335-521, 1949-1950 (Box 19, Folder 468)
  - 522-649, 1951-1952 (Box 19, Folder 469)
  - 650-733, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 470)
  - 734-817, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 471)
  - 818-894, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 472)
  - 895-959, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 473)
  - 960-1065, 1957-1958 (Box 20, Folder 474)
  - 1959-1964 (Box 20, Folder 475)
- Manuscripts, 1916-1939, undated; Series V; 0.6; (2 boxes)
  Shorter works arranged alphabetically, followed by The Oresteia.
  Davenport's prose and verse compositions. A few are holographs, but the majority are typescripts. The shorter scripts are arranged alphabetically in the first box. The second box contains various drafts of Davenport's translation of The Oresteia by Aeschylus.
  - "The Chivalric Ideal in Medieval Writers", 1923 (Box 21, Folder 476)
  - "Choral Ode", 1923 (Box 21, Folder 477)
  - "Chorus" (Mon. Tues. Wed.), undated (Box 21, Folder 478)
  - "Class Day Ode" (Taft), 1921 (Box 21, Folder 479)
  - [Debate], Euripides vs. Aeschylus, undated (Box 21, Folder 480)
  - "Epistle not to be Delivered", [1932] (Box 21, Folder 481)
  - "Everyman and Gordobuc" (school essay), undated (Box 21, Folder 482)
  - "Flight", undated (Box 21, Folder 483)
  - "Flintstone Farm", undated (Box 21, Folder 484)
  - "I Wish that I Could Send You Flowers - Those...", [1923] (Box 21, Folder 485)
  - "In Fairyland", undated (Box 21, Folder 486)
  - "Legends of Our Lady From Old France", [1918] (Box 21, Folder 487)
  - "Jason Ploughs the Earth", [1934] (Box 21, Folder 488)
  - "Lancelot, at the Chapel of the Grail", 1927 (Box 21, Folder 489)
  - "Little Red Riding Hood" - a play, undated (Box 21, Folder 490)
  - "My First Ballade", [1920] (Box 21, Folder 491)
  - "News Building" - a poem, [1932] (Box 21, Folder 492)
  - [Notes] removed from notebook, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 493)
  - "Q" - a poem, [1916] (Box 21, Folder 494)
  - Review of William Sloane's novel: The Edge of Running Water, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 495)
  - "This Calendar is Mother's Birthday Present" - a poem, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 496)
  - 'Tin is Five and Gold is Fifty..." - a poem, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 497)
  - "To Mommon" - a poem to his grandmother, undated (Box 21, Folder 498)
  - "Twas Here, 'Neath Autocratic Rule..." - a poem, undated (Box 21, Folder 499)
  - "Upon the Twenty-first of April, Sunday..." - a poem, 1927 (Box 21, Folder 500)
  - Valentines (to his mother), 1917 (Box 21, Folder 501)
  - "Le Vrai Chic Parisian", 1939 (Box 21, Folder 502)
  - "The Wall in the Woods" - a poem, [1932] (Box 21, Folder 503)
  - Translation of Aeschylus' The Oresteia First copy, 1926 (Box 22, Folder 504)
  - The Oresteia First copy draft, 1929 (Box 22, Folder 505-506)
- "His Book", 1916-1928; Series VI; 0.4; (1 box)
  Arranged chronolocially.
  A loose-leaf collection of his early verse, prose and letters. None are original and most are typed copies of items, some of which are available elsewhere in the collection. The compilation was made by Davenport's "Aunt Dudy," Mrs. Juliet (Pritte) Belknap, who died in 1948.
  - Volume I, [1916]-1927 (Box 23, Folder 507)
  - Volume II, 1927-1928 (Box 23, Folder 508)
  - Volume III, 1928 (Box 23, Folder 509)
- Printed Matter, 1920-1963; Series VII; 0.4; (2 boxes)
  Arranged roughly chronologically.
  This series contains copies of Davenport's compositions written and published at Taft and Yale; a poem incorporated in a published memorial to his aunt Ellen Scott Davison; book reviews contributed to the Saturday Review of Literature and the Book-of-the-Month Club News; letters to the editor of various publications. There are some news clippings about Davenport personally, his translation of Rostand's L'Aiglon, and his anthologies.
  - Clippings about Davenport's activities at Taft, 1920-1921 (Box 24, Folder 510)
  - Printed contributions by Davenport, 1921-1922 (Box 24, Folder 511)
    Ellen Scott Davison Memorial: "For One Lately Dead" pp 5 to 8
    The Oracle (Taft Literary Magazine): "For Memorial Day" pp15-17; Two Reviews pp 26-28
  - Clippings about Davenport's activities at Yale, 1922-1926 (Box 24, Folder 512)
  - Orations delivered at Yale, 1923, 1926 (Box 24, Folder 513)
    "In Defense of Patriotism," Parker Dickson Buck Sophomore Prize, 6p
    "Deus ex Machina," De Forest [Senior] Prize, 8p
  - Book reviews for Saturday Review, 1 for Time, 1929 (Box 24, Folder 514)
  - Book reviews for Saturday Review, 1930 (Box 24, Folder 515)
  - Book reviews for Saturday Review, 1933-1951 (Box 24, Folder 516)
  - Book review for The New York Times, 1950 (Box 24, Folder 517)
  - Articles: Creative Reading, The Blue Pencil, and Saturday Review, 1931-1936 (Box 24, Folder 518)
  - Review and columns for Book-of-the-Month News, 1950-1956, undated (Box 24, Folder 519)
  - Typed reports for Book-of-the-Month Club, 1952, undated (Box 24, Folder 520)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1937-1963 (Box 24, Folder 521)
  - General clippings about Davenport, 1926-1961 (Box 25, Folder 522)
  - Clippings on Davenport's L'Aiglon, 1925 (Box 25, Folder 523)
  - Clippings on Davenport's intro to Jane Austen's Sense and Sensibility, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 524)
  - Clippings on Davenport's Selected Works of Steven Vincent Benét, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 525)
  - Clippings on Davenport's Deals with the Devil, 1958 (Box 25, Folder 526)
  - Clippings on Davenport's "Ghost Stories", 1958 (Box 25, Folder 527)
  - Reviews of Davenport's Ghostly tales to be told; a collection of stories from the great masters, arranged for reading and telling aloud, 1950, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 528)
  - Reviews of Davenport's Great Escapes, 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 529)
  - Reviews of Davenport's "Complete A. E. Houseman", 1958 (Box 25, Folder 530)
  - Reviews of Davenport's Inquiry into Science Fiction, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 531)
  - Review of Davenport's "Invisible Man", 1960 (Box 25, Folder 532)
  - Reviews of Davenport's The Portable Roman Reader, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 533)
  - Reviews of Davenport's intro to "Science Fiction Novel", 1959 (Box 25, Folder 534)
  - Reviews of Davenport's Tales to be told in the dark; a selection of stories from the great authors, arranged for reading and telling aloud, 1953-1960 (Box 25, Folder 535)
  - Reviews of Davenport's intro to To the End of Time, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 536)
  - Reviews of Davenport's intro to "To Walk the Nights", 1954 (Box 25, Folder 537)
- Davenport Genealogy, 1899-1932; Series VIII; 0.2; (1 box)
  Material assembled by Davenport and his forbears, recording the family history and background. Except for two or three printed additions, this material is primarily in the form of correspondence with accompanying dossiers.
  - News clipping of W. B. Davenport letter, 1899 (Box 25, Folder 538)
  - 2 ALS from Bennett Franklin Davenport to Ira William Davenport, 1912 (Box 25, Folder 539)
  - TLS from Ira William Davenport to Custodian of Diamond Grove Cemetery, & reply, 1931 (Box 25, Folder 540)
  - TLS from Robert S. Franklin with dossier to Juliet (Pritte) Belknap, 1931 (Box 25, Folder 541)
  - 3 TLS from Robert S. Franklin with dossiers to Ira William Davenport, 1931-1932 (Box 25, Folder 542)
  - 2 TLS from Alice (Mack) Snyder to Ira William Davenport, 1930 (Box 25, Folder 543)
  - TL from Media Research Bureau and pamphlet to Basil Davenport, undated (Box 25, Folder 544)
  - "The Davenport's of Altona" by Boyd B. Stutler in August issue of West Virginia Review, 1932 (Box 25, Folder 545)
- Miscellany, 1920-1961; Series IX; 0.2; (1 box)
  Additional material which did not fit into any of the preceding series of the collection.
  - Royalty statements, 1954-1959 (Box 26, Folder 546)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 26, Folder 547)
  - Programs of events, 1921-1961 (Box 26, Folder 548)
  - Miscellaneous, 1920-1962, undated (Box 26, Folder 549)
    Includes a pamphlet of Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport's letters about the 1937 Louisville flood, a poem printed in a Louisville newspaper, and other memorabilia.